Dimitra Giantsidi

Email:

dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com

Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB

10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB Homepage: https://dgiantsidi.github.io/ Edinburgh, UK GitHub: https://github.com/dgiantsidi

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems!

My research lies in the field of dependability in distributed systems with focus on the fault tolerance and security. Exploring the applications of modern hardware, such as Trusted Execution Environments and Direct I/O for networking and storage, my work aims to increase the security and performance of widely adopted distributed systems. As such, I have build a few intersting systems: a secure distributed transactional store on top of Intel SGX, RDMA and LSM KVs, a shielded direct I/O network library for robust replication and a shared log system for serverless computing infrastructure on top of byte-addressable storage.

My current work focuses on the design of a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems in untrusted cloud environments.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

Sept 2019 - present

University of Edinburgh, UK

- · Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia
- · Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

MSc in Computer Science

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

University of Edinburgh, UK

· Best Performing Female MSc Thesis Award

MEng in Computer and Electrical Engineering

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

EMPLOYMENT

Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

 $Research\ Scientist\ Intern$

 \cdot Design of KVs for timing attacks.

University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - present

Research Assistant

 \cdot Hardware/software co-design of a trusted NIC architecture.

Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

Software & Systems Engineer

 \cdot Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- · Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

PUBLICATIONS

Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture.

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

SIGMOD'24

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing.

Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.

ACM HPDC'23

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions.

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System.

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

USENIX ATC'21

DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation.

 $Konstantinos\ Nikas,\ Nikela\ Papadopoulou,\ Dimitra\ Giantsidi,\ Vasileios\ Karakostas,\ Georgios\ Goumas,\ Nectarios\ Koziris.$

ICPP'19

TALKS

ACM HPDC'23, Orlando, US

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing.

IEEE/IFIP DSN'22, Baltimore, US

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions.

Third Annual SGX Community Day 2022 (virtual)

USENIX ATC'21 (virtual) Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java, Vitis HLS

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control Git

Distributed Programming Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EuroSys'21

Web chair.

EuroSys'23, SoCC'23, WWW'22

 $Shadow\ PC\ member.$

HONORS AND AWARDS

Microsoft Research Award	2019
Best Performing Female MSc Student Award, University of Edinburgh	2019
Highest Honors award	2012